luonline.com 2018-11-19

# Privacy Policy | University Offices | Liberty University

This is a summary of Liberty University's Privacy Policy. You may [view the full privacy policy](https://www.liberty.edu/administration/institutionaleffectiveness/index.cfm?PID=30130#/policy/347) here.

## Policy Statement

Liberty University monitors and collects various types of information from our website visitors for legal and policy compliance, for the maintenance and security of the network, and so we can adjust our websites to meet our users' needs and expectations. Some of this information is collected automatically and other information is provided by site users. The university reserves the right to restrict the use of its information technology resources and to remove or limit access to information technology resources.

## Information Collected Automatically

The University collects limited, non-personal identifying information your browser makes available when visiting websites. We may aggregate this non-identifying information for reporting purposes to assess the effectiveness of our websites without disclosing specific information that would link to any individual. This includes:

  * Your Internet Protocol address
  * The Browser type (Internet Explorer, Firefox, etc.)
  * Your computer’s operating system (Windows, Macintosh, etc.)
  * Your Internet domain (AOL, EarthLink, etc.)
  * Your mobile device (iPhone, Tablet, etc.)
  * URLs of the websites you come to our websites from
  * Cookie information described below
  * The pages on our website that you visit including date and time of access
  * Geographic vicinity and other demographic and interests information

## Use of Cookies

In some instances, our websites use cookies that uniquely identify your browser so that we may provide content most relevant to your needs. A cookie allows the University website to customize what you see in relation to the way you entered the website and content that you recently viewed (i.e., if you logged into your student account, the website may be personalized for student viewing in subsequent visits).

## Information You Provide to Us

You provide information to Liberty when you fill out online forms and browse our websites or use a login-required service. Depending on the type of the service, we use your information in different ways as outlined below.

### Inquiry and Application Forms

  * Information that you choose to complete, which may include your name, e-mail address, phone number, and content of the e-mail, are used in order to provide information about the University.
  * If you do not wish to provide your contact information online, you may call the University and request that information be sent through the mail.

### Purchasing Merchandise or Donating to the University

  * Information that you choose to complete, which may include your name, e-mail address, phone number, mailing and/or billing address, credit or debit card information are used to send merchandise to you, and to contact you if necessary.
  * Your financial information is used for billing.
  * Any information about a third party you are including as a beneficiary.
  * If you do not wish to provide your contact or financial information online, you may call the University to place an order or donate.

### Login Sites and Services

  * Various websites and web services of Liberty University require users to log in to gain access to information and tools reserved for students, faculty and staff.

### Web Engagement Data

  * Your engagement data (i.e. analytic info, referral data, form data, etc.) may be used to personalize our communications with you.

Information you provide may be used by the University for marketing purposes. If at any point you wish to discontinue receiving marketing e-mails or phone calls, you may use the opt out feature on our e-mails or call the University at (800) 543-5317 or (800) 424-9595. Liberty University never blends their collection data with Google. See the below section on Google Data (below) for information on Google’s Privacy and Terms or to opt out of their automatic data collection.

## Specific Concerns

Liberty University websites have standard security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. For example, we utilize industry standard SSL encryption when accepting your credit card information during the online ordering process, as well as whenever we ask you to log in to any of the University's online student and faculty services.

Liberty University does not sell, rent, or share your personal information to any outside organizations. Liberty will abide by all applicable laws governing the release of personal information.

Collective information about site users – but never individuals’ personal information – is used in marketing, advertising and other relationships with third parties.

Liberty University does not merge any personal information that you provide with any non-personal information provided by your browser. The university does not collect client or user identifiers that Google assigns in order to calculate unique and repeat visitors. Conversely, Liberty University does not upload any personal data or identifiers it assigns that might likewise allow Google to personally identify any individual.

## How Liberty University Uses Your Information

Liberty University uses information collected automatically to better understand the needs of website visitors so that we may improve our websites and services.

Information you provide may be used by the university for marketing purposes.

### Google data

Google gathers information about users of its technologies to improve the online experience and help website owners understand how visitors engage with their sites. Liberty University uses many such product offerings including Google Analytics Demographic and Interest Reporting, Display Network Impression Reporting, Remarketing and Advertiser Features, DoubleClick Platform integrations, and Reporting APIs. To better support some features the university implemented Google’s Universal Analytics and enabled UserID, an identifier Google assigns to determine unique users across devices.

However UserID cannot be queried in the Reporting API and the university itself does not otherwise capture, use, or merge Google’s unique identifiers nor does it upload or otherwise share with Google or third party vendors any personal identifiers or information that you provide as is outlined in this document.

Liberty University encourages its website visitors to learn more about how Google uses data and how you can control the information sent through your browser by viewing [Google’s Privacy & Terms](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/) page. Users who wish to learn more about opting out of the automatic collection and use of data on the web should visit [Google’s Consumer Ads Help Center](https://support.google.com/ads/%23topic=2941003) or [Opt Out](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en&ref_topic=2941003) here.

We may release personal information when necessary to comply with the law, respond to judicial process, or provide information to law enforcement or regulatory agencies; enforce our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Liberty University, our faculty, staff, users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Facebook pixels are used to collect information from visitors to Liberty University’s websites to be utilized for targeted marketing purposes. [Facebook’s Business Tools Terms](https://www.facebook.com/legal/businesstech) outlines how Facebook collects pixels. An opt out is available through <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

## K-12 school sites

### Liberty University Online Academy

The **Liberty University Online Academy** ([www.libertyonlineacademy.com](http://www.libertyonlineacademy.com/)) offers programs for students in grades K- 12. It collects personal identifying information through its inquiry and application forms. Although the forms ask for the personal information of the parent or guardian, not the child, Liberty University Online Academy realizes that children may occasionally fill out and submit these forms. Liberty University upholds the confidentiality of any and all information obtained from parents in the course of gaining parental consent or providing for parental access.

Parents may ask to have the child’s personal identifying information deleted by using the contact information below.

Website operator:  
Liberty University Online Academy  
1971 University Boulevard  
Lynchburg, VA 24515  
(866) 418-8741  

Personal information collected on the Liberty University Online Academy website is not shared with third parties.

### Liberty Christian Academy

Liberty Christian Academy ([www.lcabulldogs.com](http://www.lcabulldogs.com/)) is an affiliated traditional private grade school whose website resides on Liberty University’s domain. Liberty Christian Academy does not collect personal identifying information online but only provides printable forms to submit offline.

Liberty University limits the collection or use of non-personal information your browser makes available when visiting the websites of our affiliated K-12 grade schools by restricting reporting features that can be applied to these sites. Guardians are encouraged to visit Google’s online [Safety Center](http://www.google.com/intl/en/safetycenter/families/start/) to learn more about further provisions they can employ to restrict the collection of data on minors.

## How to Update Your Information

Our student and faculty services sites, including ASIST, provide you with the option of changing and modifying information you have previously provided to us.

## Changes to This Policy

Liberty’s Privacy Policy attempts to maintain, but cannot guarantee, continued access to [Google’s opt out](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en&ref_topic=2941003) feature and policy documentation. Access is available through Google’s site and users are encouraged to remain familiar with Google’s documentation of what opting out does and does not do.

The university reserves the right to append or otherwise modify its Privacy Policy at any time. We expect any such changes to be minor, and notification of all changes will be made on this page. Each version of the Privacy Policy will be dated at the bottom of the page.

* * *

Updated July, 2015
